A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1974-1975
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1974-1975
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.773
This collection consists of 8,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 21 July 1977.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- "A-Al" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  Alcohol Beverage Control Board re: Newcomb Hall ABC License, Correspondence from Edgar F. Shannon (Former University President) and Mrs. Hugh Bullock (President of American Association of Poets) Concerning Renewal of American Poets' Poetry Prize at the University from 1975-1979, President Hereford's Acknowledgment for the Alcoa Foundation's Gift to the University, Transactions Culminating in the Establishment of the John S. Alfriend Lecture Fund
- "Am" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  Correspondence re: the Reappointment of Anntte Gibbs as the Corporate Representative of the American Association of the University Women, Correspondence from the American Cancer Society Approving Grants for the Varying Areas of Cancer Research
- "An-Az" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  Correspondence--Anderson Brothers' Book Store Gift to the Law School
- Academic Deans 1974-1975 (Box 1)
- Admissions "A-P" (Restricted) 1974-1975 (Box 1)
- Admissions "R-Z" (Restricted) 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- Admissions 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  Typical Problem Cases
- Admissions 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  General--Admission of Athletes, University Agrees to be a Participant in Project Ahead (U.S. Army on Cooperative Education)
- Admissions--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- Air Force Academy 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- Alumni Association--General 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- Alumni Fund 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  Virginia National Bank Summary of Investments, Expenses on 1974 and Proposed 1975 Budget, Auditor's Report and Financial Expose of Alumni Fund
- Alumni GPS Luncheon--February 19, 1975 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- American Association of University Professors--Annual Compensation Survey, Annual Survey of Academic Salary and Fringe Benefit Data 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- American Council on Education 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Annual Reports--Equal Opportunities Program Report, Reports of Different Branches of the University 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Annual Reports--President 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Anthropology 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Applications for Positions 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Architecture--General--Landscape Architecture Accreditation Confirmation, Trust Check in Support of the Cary D. Langhorne Chair in Architecture 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Architecture--Personnel (Empty) 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Army--General 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Army--JAG School 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Art--Bayly Museum--Acknowledgment of the Reception of Art Objects for Charles Barham, Jr., Samuel M. Kootz, The Chrysler Museum at Norfolk, Mr. Myron Brody 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Art--Commission 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Art--General 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Asian Studies 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Association of American Colleges 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Association of American Universities--Record of Hereford's Senate Committee Testimony 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- AAU-Executive Committee 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- AAU--Federal Relations Committee 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Association of Virginia Colleges 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Astronomy 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Athletics--ACC--Minutes of the ACC Conference 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Athletics--Finance 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Athletics--General--Report on "The Neale Years" in Football 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Athletics--NCAA--Article on President Hereford's Boating Accident 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Athletics--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Atomic Energy Commission--University of Virginia Special Citation for its Contribution to the Uranium Enrichment Program 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Attorney General--State--President Hereford's Rebuttal of Accusations of University Administrative Personnel of "Unauthorized Practice of Law" 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Audit Reports 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Automated Data Processing--State--General Assembly of Virginia House Appropriations Committee Staff Report 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- "B-Bm" Miscellaneous--Correspondence Concerning Gift to Nuclear Engineering Department, Acknowledgment of the Foundation of the Robert Beaurline Scholarship, Acknowledgment of Bell Telephone Laboratories for an Unrestricted Grant to a University Student 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- "Bn-Bz" Miscellaneous--President Hereford's Acknowledgment of Brown and Williamson's Unrestricted Grant to the University, Correspondence Relating to Carr's Hill Dinner Party Honoring William Buckley and David Halberstam 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Barco, James W. (Counselor to the President) 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Biology--General 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Boar's Head Inn 1968-1969--Report and Correspondence Concerning Possible Land Transaction of Birdwood from the University to the Boar's Head Inn (Permanent) 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Budget--General--Correspondence Indicating the University's Aid in Helping the University of California System Set-Up State Budgeting Practice 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Budget--Capital Outlay 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Budget--Medical 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Buildings and Grounds 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Buildings and Grounds--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Bursar 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Business and Finance 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- Business Manager 1974-1975 (Box 5)
- "Ca-Ck" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  Camp Family History of the University; Acknowledgment of the Union-Camp Corporation's Gift of the Library to the Colgate Darden Business School and Donation; Recommendations to the Century Association (Andrew Miller and R. Phillip Hanes, Jr.); Christmas Card Addressed to the Herefords from Warren Chappel; Joint Will of the Warren Chappels Providing for an Artist-in-Residence; Receipt of Check from Marjorie S. Charles Foundation; Charlottesville Rescue Squad Receipt of $200.00 Donation from the University; Acknowledgment of Research Grant from the Chevron Research Corporation
- "Cl-Cz" Miscellaneous--Acknowledgment of the Check Constituting the Gertrude Watchler Cohen Memorial Foundation; Correspondence Expressing Gratitude for the Grant from Combustion Engineering, Inc.; Minutes of the Board of Directors Meeting of the Council of Southern Universities; Correspondence Acknowledging the west and Cumming Donation of Books to Alderman Library. 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Career Planning and Placement 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Cavalier Daily 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Center for Advanced Studies 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Center for Studies in Humanistic Sources 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Chemistry--General 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Civil Rights--General 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Classics (Empty) 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Clinch Valley College--General 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Clinch Valley College--Personnel (Restricted) 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- College of Arts and Sciences 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- College Entrance Examination Board 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Commerce--General 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Commerce--Personnel (Empty) 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Admissions--Minutes of April 21, 1975 Admissions Committee Meeting; Report on Committee Activities for Spring Semester 1974-1975 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Arboretum--Minutes of 1974-75 Meetings and First and Second Semester Reports, History of the O.E. White Arboretum 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Architectural Advisory 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Athletic Advisory Council 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Calendar and Scheduling--Minutes of March 21, 1975 Meeting; Feb 25, 1975; Feb 29, 1972; March 29, 1972; April 27, 1972; May 17, 1972; and Oct 21, 1972 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Career Planning and Placement 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Catalogue 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Cemetery 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Chapel--Minutes of Nov 30, 1973; March 21, 1974; and Sep 25, 1974 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Community Colleges--Minutes of March 5, 1975 and December 11, 1974 Meetings 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Computers--Minutes of Oct 31, 1974 Meeting 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--Danforth Fellowships 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Committee--EEOOR--Report on Black Experience at UVA, Report on the Status of Women Faculty at UVA 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Fraternities 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee Fulbright Grants 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Future of the University--Minutes of Jan 24, 1975 Meeting; First Annual Report of the Committee 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Graduate Opportunities 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Gwathmey Awards 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Housing--Minutes of Nov 18, 1974 Meeting 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Institutional Analysis--Correspondence re: Dissolvance of the Committee 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--International Students 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Thomas Jefferson Award 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Lectures--Page, Barbour, and Richard 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Lectures--Special 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Library 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Master Plan--Minutes of Oct 14, 1974 Meeting 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Museum 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Names 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Patents 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Processions 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Public Occasions--Minutes of April 25, 1975 Meeting 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Radiation Safety 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Records 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Registration 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--ROTC 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Scholarships, Grant-in-Aid, Loans, and Employment 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Security and General Safety--Condensed Minutes of Oct 2 and Dec 11, 1974 and Feb 12 and April 19, 1975 Meetings 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Student Activities 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Student Health 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Student Rights and Responsibilities 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Summer Grants 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Summer Session 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Teacher Education--Minutes of April 2, 1975 Meeting 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Traffic and Parking--Condensed Notes of May 14, 1975 Traffic and Parking Meeting; Minutes of March 6, March 20, and Feb 20 Meetings; Condensed Notes from Oct 4, 1974 Meeting 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--Traffic Appeals 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--University Committee on Students 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--University Development Steering 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Committee--University Press 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Committee--University Union--Minutes of Sep 26, Oct 14, Nov 20, Dec 11, 1974 and Jan 22, Feb 12, April 9, and April 23, 1975 Meetings 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Committee--Virginia Quarterly Review 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Committee--Virginia Status of University Students--Condensed Notes from July 15, 1975 Meeting 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Community Colleges 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Comptroller--State 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Comptroller--University 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Computing Activities 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Congress 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Consortia--General 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Consortium--Capitol 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Consortium--Central Virginia 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Consortium--Northern Virginia 1974-1975 (Box 8)
- Consortium--Tidewater 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Consortium--Valley 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Consortium--Western 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Continuing Education--Center in Northern Virginia 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Continuing Education--F.B.I. National Academy 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Continuing Education--General 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Continuing Education--Personnel (Restricted) 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Continuing Education--Richmond Regional Center 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Council of Presidents 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Council of Southern Universities 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Council on the Environment 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Counsel to President for Special Development 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- "Da-De" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- "Df-Dz" Miscellaneous--History of Duke University; Grant of $15,00 from the DuPont Company 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Danforth Foundation 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Degrees 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Development 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Development--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Ditchley Foundation 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- Drama 1974-1975 (Box 9)
- "E" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  Correspondence Acknowledging Mrs. Patricia J. Edgerton's Gift to the Rare Book Library Fund, Correspondence Thanking Mrs. K.M. Eustace for Her Commemorative Gift to the University; Acknowledgment of Exxon's Designated Contribution
- Economics 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Education--General 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Education--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Energy Office--State 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Engineering 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Engineering--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Engineering and Buildings 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Engineering Science Research Labs 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- English 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Enrollment 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Environmental Sciences 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Equal Opportunity--Registry 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- "F" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  Correspondence Acknowledging the Fleet Foundation Scholarship, Acknowledgment to Mrs. C.T. Montgomery for Her Continued Payment for the Harry D. Forsyth Eminent Scholars Chair in Engineering, Report of the Fourth-Year Servicemen's Opportunity College Project
- Faculty--General--Federal Executive Institute re: Architecture 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Faculty--Meetings 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Faculty--Orientation and Reception 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Faculty--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Federal Executive Institute 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Fellowship--DuPont Regional 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Fellowship--Love 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Fellowship--Rhodes 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Fellowships and Scholarships 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Financial Aid to Students 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- Fraternities (Permanent) 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- French Literature 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- "G" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  General Electric Corporate Alumnus Program Gift, Grant from General Services Administration for the Papers of James Madison Project, Correspondence re: Duke of Gloucester's Visit, Correspondence re: Grant from Gulf Oil Foundation for Dr. Hunt's Research
- Gay Student Union 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- General Assembly 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- General Assembly--House Appropriations 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- George Mason University 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Germanic Literature 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Gifts and Grants--Correspondence 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Government and Foreign Affairs 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Governor 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Governor--Administrative 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Governor--Education 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Governor--Transportation and Public Safety--Correspondence re: Part of the School of Continuing Education Designated as an Emergency Operations Center 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Graduate Business Sponsors--Report on Examination Year Ended June 30, 1974 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Graduate School of Arts and Sciences--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Graduate School of Business Administration 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Graphic Communications Services 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Green, Julian H.-- Liberte, Book by Green; Nomination of Green by Shannon (UVA President) for Nobel Prize; Correspondence from Green Thanking President Shannon for the Nomination 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Guggenheim Foundation 1974-1975 (Box 13)
- "H" Miscellaneous--Report on Higher Education Accessibility Projects 1974-1975 (Box 13)
- Hereford, Frank L., Jr.--Article re: Noise from Vortex-Line Turbulence in He II; Acceptance of Honorary Fellowship in the Society of Fellows; Article on President Hereford in The Virginia -Pilot; Contracts of the Sale of President Hereford's Land to Mr. Warren Wakeman 1974-1975 (Box 13)
- Hereford--Carr's Hill--Bills 1974-1975 (Box 13)
- Hereford--Congratulation Letters on Selection as President 1974-1975 (Box 13)
- Hereford--Congratulation Letters on Selection as President (2 folders) 1974-1975 (Box 14)
- Hereford--Correspondence re: Farmington Decision 1974-1975 (Box 14)
- Hereford--Inauguration Committee 1974-1975 (Box 14)
- Hereford--Inauguration Congratulations 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Hereford--Inauguration List 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Highway Department 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Highway Research Council 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- History--Correspondence re: President Hereford's Efforts to Reunite Professor W. McClellan and His Russian Wife 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Honor System and Honor Committee 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Hospital 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Hospital--Operating Budget and Reports 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Hospital--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Housing 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- "I" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Institute of Government 1974-1975 (Box 15)
- Institutional Analysis 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- "J" Miscellaneous--Minutes of the Thomas Jefferson Planning District Commission of Dec 3, 1974 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- "K" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Kenan Charitable Trust 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- "L" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 16)
  Correspondence re: Permission Granted to James Lincoln (Artist) to Paint the University-encl. a Poem and Biography of Lincoln; Loki Magazine
- Law--Admissions (Restricted) 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Law--Enforcement Education Program 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Law--General 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Law--Law School Foundation 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Law--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Legal Adviser 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Legal Estates--Will of Claudia Palmer Young 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Library--Associate of the Library 1974-1975 (Box 16)
- Library--General 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Library--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- "Mc" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- "Mi-Mz" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- McGregor Fund 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- McIntire Fund 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Madison House 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Marine Science 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Mary Washington College 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Medical Center--General 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Medical Education Liaison Committee 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Medical School 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Medical School--Admissions 1974-1975 (Box 17)
- Medical School--Faculty Promotion Proposals 1974-1975 (Box 18)
- Medical School--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 18)
- Michigan State University Collective Bargaining 1974-1975 (Box 18)
- Music 1974-1975 (Box 18)
- "Na" Miscellaneous--Correspondence re: National Gallery of Art's Exhibition The Eye of Thomas Jefferson and the Borrowing of Art Objects from the University 1974-1975 (Box 18)
- "Ne-Nz" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 18)
- National Aeronautics and Space Administration 1974-1975 (Box 18)
- NASUL--Advancement of Public Negro Colleges 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- NASUL--Circular Letter (Empty) 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- NASUL--General 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- NASUL--Institutional Research 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- NASUL--International Letters (Empty) 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- National Endowment for Humanities 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- National Historical Publications Commission 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- National Humanities Center 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- National Medal of Science 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- National Science Foundation 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- National War College 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Naval War College 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Newcomb Hall 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Newcomen Society 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Nursing 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Nursing--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- "O" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Oceanic Educational Foundation 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Omicron Delta Kappa 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- "P" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Parking and Transit 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 19)
- Personnel--Employee Relations 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Phi Beta Kappa 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Phi Beta Kappa--Associates 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Philosophy 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Physics--General 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Physics--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Planning--State--Federal Programs Listing Management Information Series 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Planning--University 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Project Status Reports 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Promotions 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Provost 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Psychology 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Public Affairs 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Purchasing 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- Questionnaires 1974-1975 (Box 20)
- "R" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 20)
  Correspondence re: Inquiry into the Second Restoration of General Robert E. Lee's Citizenship, Biographical Sketch of Walter Reed
- Recommendations "A-Z" 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Registrar--General 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Registrar--Space Reservation Requests 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Rehabilitation Center 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Religious Studies 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- ROTC 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- ROTC--Air Force 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- ROTC--Army 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- ROTC--Navy 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- "S-Sl" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 21)
  Correspondence re: Establishment of the Robert David Saltz Memorial Fellowship, Correspondence re: Contention Over Wording of Woodrow Wilson's Plaque in Rotunda by Catherine Schoeffler
- "Sm-Sz" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Safety and Security 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Salaries 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Senate--University--Minutes of March 18, April 16, May 6, 1975 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Seven Society 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Slavic Languages and Literature 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Sociology 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Southern Fellowship Fund 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Southern Regional Education Board 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Space Administrator 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Special Programs 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Special Programs--Action 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Special Programs--Summer Work, Study Preparatory Program--Report on Audit 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Speech Pathology and Audiology 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Speeches 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- Sponsored Programs 1974-1975 (Box 22)
- State Council of Higher Education (SCHE) 1974-1975 (Box 23)
- State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)---Draft for Discussion Purpose Nov 8, 1974 1974-1975 (Box 23)
- State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)--News Releases and Council Notes 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- State Department of Education 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Student Affairs 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Student Affairs--Personnel 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Student Council 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Student Council--Minutes (Empty) 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Student Health Department 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Student Legal Forum 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Summer Session 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- "T" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Tayloe Murphy Institute 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Transportation 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Travel Invoices 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Travel Reimbursements--Frank L. Hereford, Jr. 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- Treasurer--University 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- "U" Miscellaneous 1974-1975 (Box 24)
  1974 U.S. Army Year-End Report, Pamphlet on Army Education Services Plan, Pamphlet on UVA Credit Union
- U.S. Congress 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- U.S. Department Agriculture 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare 1974-1975 (Box 25)
- U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare--Dr. Severinson Correspondence 1974-1975 (Box 25)
- Universities Research Association 1974-1975 (Box 25)